complaints.com 2001-06-07

# Complaints.com Privacy Statement

This privacy statement applies specifically to the Complaints.com service. Questions regarding this statement should be directed to [info@complaints.com](mailto:info@complaints.com).  

It's important to Comments.com, Inc., which owns and operates the Complaints.com service, ("Complaints.com") to help its customers retain their privacy when they take advantage of all the Internet has to offer. What this means to you is, we are committed to protecting your privacy and developing technology that gives you the most powerful, safe, online experience that you can get anywhere. 

By default, your name and e-mail address will be posted for public view on Complaints.com. This is so other consumers can contact you with any help regarding your message.

If you don't want your name or e-mail address posted to Complaints.com, please just tell Complaints.com not to post that information. If you change your mind later, just let us know, and your name and e-mail address will be removed.

Privacy Principles

Because your privacy is important to us, Complaints.com operates by the following principles:

Principle 1.

Complaints.com explicitly asks when it needs information that personally identifies you ("New User Information"). Complaints.com asks for your first and last name, state and zip code (or country and postal code for non-U.S. residents), and active email address. You may update this information at any time from within your Complaints.com account by clicking the "More..." button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the "Edit Your Profile" link.

Principle 2.

Your Profile Information is used for demographic statistics and to display appropriate individualized advertisements. The Complaints.com site uses your name and e-mail address to identify you as a user of the site to other users of the Complaints.com service. Users may chose to exclude their e-mail address from public view by clicking the "More..." button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the "Edit Your Profile" link.

Your Profile Information, and the content of your message, is also provided to businesses that are the subject of the complaints that you post to Complaints.com. This information is also provided to select other businesses, as determined by Complaints.com, but it is only provided in aggregrate, anonymous form.

Providing subject businesses with you profile information is necessary, of course, in order to allow businesses to contact you directly, via email, in response to your message posted to the Complaints.com site. This direct consumer consumer contact by businesses is one of the important purposes of this site - to notify businesses about consumer complaints. Complaints.com in not responsible for providing or helping to provide businesses' responses to consumer complaints posted the Complaints.com site.  

Your user name and email address is always available for public view on the Complaints.com site. This helps encourage the authentication, accountability, and constructiveness of user content, including posted messages, e-mails, pages, chat sessions and all other activities performed on the Complaints.com site. This also encourages community building among site members; site members sharing information and complaints about products and services.  

Otherwise, Complaints.com keeps all of your Profile Information private and does not share it with any third parties. Complaints.com will not disclose your Profile Information unless acting under a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (1) conform to legal requirements or comply with legal process; (2) protect and defend the rights or property of Complaints.com; (3) enforce the Complaints.com Terms of Service; or (4) act to protect the interests of its members or others.

Principle 3.

Complaints.com will not send you any unsolicited information, including e-mail, except as mentioned below. New users will receive a Complaints.com welcome e-mail explaining the features provided by the service, and containing your username and password. The information contained in this welcome e-mail is required to log-on a registered user of the Complaints.com site.  

Complaints.com will not send you unsolicited e-mail regarding any commercial offers or advertisements at any time. Complaints.com may send you e-mail to announce information relating to the Complaints.com service and/or changes and improvements to the Complaints.com service.

Principle 4.

If at any time you believe that Complaints.com has not adhered to these principles, please notify us by e-mail at info@Complaints.com and we will use all commercially reasonable efforts to promptly determine and correct the problem.  

If you have questions about this policy, please e-mail us at [info@complaints.com](mailto:info@complaints.com).  

For more information about our privacy statement, see the following Frequently Asked Questions (FAQs).

Frequently Asked Questions  

**What about Cookies?**  

Cookies are pieces of information that a Web site transfers to your computer's hard disk for record-keeping purposes. Cookies can make the Web more useful by storing information about your preferences on a particular site. The use of cookies is an industry standard, and many major Web sites use them to provide useful features for their customers. Cookies in and of themselves do not personally identify users, although they do identify a user's computer. Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. If you'd prefer, you can set yours to refuse cookies. However, you may not be able to take full advantage of a Web site if you do so.

**What about the Privacy of children?**

Safeguarding the Profile Information of children is extremely important. Complaints.com collects the minimum amount of Profile Information necessary to operate the service. A child's Profile Information will be used for operation of the service but it will never be used for uses related to the site's service but not necessary to its operation (a "Secondary Use").

**Does Complaints.com collect other forms of information about its users?**

In addition to the use of Profile Information to operate the site, Complaints.com also gathers anonymous information, which may be used by Complaints.com or shared with its advertisers. This is information which does not personally identify you, but which may be helpful for marketing purposes or for improving the services we offer. Generally, this information is collected through "traffic data" and may entail the use of "Cookies", "IP addresses" or other numeric codes used to identify a computer.

**How do I correct or change Profile Information that I have given to Complaints.com?**

You may update this information at any time from within your Complaints.com account by clicking the "More..." button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the "Edit Your Profile" link.

**Is my Profile Information secure from others using the Complaints.com site?**

Profile Information collected by Complaints.com is by default available to other Complaints.com users to promote community and the free exchange of ideas. Users can choose to hide their email address from other users by clicking the "More..." button on the navigation bar, and then clicking on the "Edit Your Profile" link.

However, your user name is always available for public view on the Complaints.com site. This helps encourage the authentication, accountability, and constructiveness of user content, including posted messages, e-mails, pages, chat sessions and all other activities performed on the Complaints.com site.

**How else might someone learn of my Profile Information while visiting another site?**

In addition to directly providing information to Complaints.com, you might also provide Profile Information through chat sessions, e-mail exchanges or bulletin board use made available to you on other sites, including other Complaints.com sites. Chat sessions and bulletin board or newsgroup use is considered public and you are responsible for your actions in these areas. The Complaints.com Privacy Statement does not cover this type of transfer of your Profile Information. You should always be careful when distributing your Profile Information in this manner.

Our Web site uses a reputable third party to serve the advertisements that you see on the pages of our Web site. If you would like to know more about the information gathering practices and "opt-out" procedures of our third party ad server, please click here. 

"Complaints.com Consumer Complaints Database - Your Platform for Better Customer Service uses WebTrends Live to analyze traffic to this web site. WebTrends Live does not create individual profiles for visitors. Unlike some tracking services WebTrends Live does not have a database of individual profiles for each visitor. WebTrends Live only collects aggregate data. For more information about WebTrends Live privacy policy, please click here."
